Jeff Li . Jarvis Consulting

I am a graduate of the University of Toronto with a bachelor's degree in Computer Science. The whole reason I am interested in Computer Science, in general, is the fact that there is such a wide application of the profession. I have experience working in agile scrum teams both as a developer and a QA. Outside of work, I have an interest in Gaming, Game Design, Reading, as well as history. What makes me enthusiastic about working in data engineering is that only for the past few decades does there exist recorded data that can be used in the way of "data engineering" making this a new and interesting frontier that I am interested in being a part of.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Bash, SQL, Agile/Scrum, Python, System security, OOP, JIRA, React, Javascript, Git, Data structures

Competent: RESTful APIs, TDD programming, PHP, NPM, IntelliJ/PHP Storm, Visual Studio Code, Docker

Familiar: C, SSH, Node.js

Development Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis data eng jeff

- Cluster Monitor: Wrote a continuous monitoring of multiple web servers and their CPU output so as to be able to provide updates about how the CPU for each is doing. The project is implemented in Bash scripts, hosted on a docker container, and uses the cronjob scheduler.
- Core Java Apps: Created a collection of individual smaller projects that are designed to help learn about lambda functions, DAO access patterns as well as RESTful API calls. These skills are learned through the implementation of command-line grep, and Twitter GET POST and DELETE service.
- SpringBoot App: Not startedCloud & DevOps: Not started

Hadoop: Not started Spark/Scala: Not started

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis, Toronto (2020-Present): Developing projects utilizing various core big data technologies such as cloud, DevOps, Java, Hadoop & Spark. Performing the duties of scrum master in agile-based team projects to ensure team cohesion, collaboration, and overall success at the workplace.

Software Developer, Bold Commerce, Winnipeg (2018-2019): Built and improved multiple user interfaces to improve customer usability and clarity as well as diagnosed and hotfixed multiple incorrect scripts recording incorrect data. Later, aided with redevelopment and refactoring of older apps translating them from PHP to react to improve speed and reliability.

Quality Assurance Analyst, SecureFact, Toronto (2016-2017): Worked in a scrum agile environment interacting with Business Analysts and Developers to test code with multiple different APIs for ensuring the functionality of projects.

Education & Academic Projects

University of Toronto (2016-2020), Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

- Mock Linux Command Line Interface: Developed a mock Linux command-line interface that handled basic bash commands like mkdir, 1s and 1n. The CLI mocked similar behaviour as a proper Linux file system in functionality as well as memory management. The project was developed in C so to be able to control memory storage.
- Hacking CTF challenges: Worked on various capture the flag hacking challenges involved with breaking through basic security. Challenges included various security exploits such as packet sniffing, cross-site scripting, and SQL injections.
- Developer, WorldScribe website 2019: Developed a writer's tool to track storytelling elements by tracking story elements (ie, characters, settings) in an accessible manner. I was involved with developing the front-end written in React with Material-UI interface, helping and designing the layout and interfaces of the project.